Can we make our coffee taste better by brewing the same grounds twice?
You see this a lot with tea where it's re-steeped, but we want to try it with coffee. Using the Harrier switch
We're going to do a traditional pour over. We're using 15 grams of coffee and to that
We're going to add 240 grams of water. We're going to start with the classic bloom. 50 grams
And we're going to leave that for 30 seconds and at the 30 second mark
We're going to top that up to 240 grams. Now we're going to close this switch
This will allow us to do an immersion for the second brew, but we're not using water for the second grounds
We're going to pour the coffee back through the bed
Then we're going to steep that for 30 seconds at the 30 second mark
We're going to open the switch and allow that to drain. Is it better now?
We'll taste just the regular filter coffee
It's nice clean black current and now we'll taste the double brewed coffee
You're probably getting a few negative characteristics coming through from that second brew
But there is a lot more sweetness if you value body and sweetness
This is a really good way to increase that in your coffee coffee undecided